Preliminary Inventory of the Paderewski Testimonial Fund Records, 1911-2005
Hoover Institution Archives
Paderewski Testimonial Fund Records,
1911-2005
59024
Paderewski Testimonial Fund
81 manuscript boxes, 4 oversize boxes, 5 card file drawers, 1 scrapbook, 3 phonorecords (36.8 linear feet)
Hoover Institution Archives Stanford, California 94305-6010
Reports, correspondence, press releases, financial records, printed matter, and photographs, relating to relief activities carried on by the Fund and by the Paderewski Hospital in Edinburgh, Scotland.
Administrative Information
Access
Collection open for research.
The Hoover Institution Archives only allows access to copies of audiovisual items. To listen to sound recordings or to view videos or films during your visit, please contact the Archives at least two working days before your arrival. We will then advise you of the accessibility of the material you wish to see or hear. Please note that not all audiovisual material is immediately accessible.
Acquisition Information
Materials were acquired by the Hoover Institution Archives in 1959.
Accruals
Materials may have been added to the collection since this finding aid was prepared. To determine if this has occurred, find the collection in Stanford University's online catalog at http://searchworks.stanford.edu/. Materials have been added to the collection if the number of boxes listed in the online catalog is larger than the number of boxes listed in this finding aid.
Access Points
Paderewski Hospital.; International relief.; Poles in foreign countries.; Refugees.; World War, 1939-1945--Civilian relief.; World War, 1939-1945.; Poland.; Great Britain.; Phonorecords.
Container List
- Administrative Material (Box 1)
  - Incorporation papers (Delaware, 1941 March 14)
  - Board of Directors meeting minutes
  - Executive Committee meeting minutes, 1941-1944 (#1)
  - Board of Directors meeting minutes
  - Executive Committee meeting minutes, 1945-1948
  - Treasurer's Report, etc. (#2)
  - Same, 1947-1954 (#3)
  - Executive Committee meetings - Incorporation papers, 1941 (#4)
- Board of Directors - Executive Committee (Box 2)
  - Francis N. Bangs - Attorney (dissolution of funds) (#1)
  - Deceased members - Paderewski Fund, 1946-1947 (#2)
  - Board of Directors of Paderewski Fund, 1941-1949 (#3)
  - Executive Committee (#4)
  - James F. Best, 1943-1948 (#5)
  - Honorable Robert Woods Bliss
    - 1948- (#6)
    - 1939-1941 (#7)
  - Calvin Bullock, 1941-1942 - Treasurer (#8)
  - Doda Conrad, New York City - Vice-Chairman (#9)
  - Hugh Gibson - member of Executive Committee and Board of Directors, Vice-Chairman (#10)
  - C. E. Gross - Treasurer (National City Bank for Basic Orders) (#11)
  - Dr. Arthur Hunter - Treasurer, 1943-1946 (#12)
  - Huger W. Jervey, 1941-1949 - member of Board of Directors and Executive Committee (#13)
  - Mrs. Vernon Charlotte Kellogg - Chairman (Board of Directors, Executive Committee) (#14)
  - Arthur Bliss Lane, 1950-1951 (#15)
  - Honorable Arthur Bliss Lane, 1947-1949 (#1) (Box 3)
  - Bryce Le Jeune - Member of Board of Directors and Executive Committee (#2)
  - I. Nurkiewicz, 1951 (#3)
  - John Donald Robb, 1941 - Board of Directors and Executive Committee (#4)
  - Herbert L. Satterlee, 1939-1946 (#5)
  - Mrs. Ernest Schelling - Member of Board of Directors, Executive Committee, Chairman of New York City Committee (#6)
  - Mrs. Catherine Hughes Waddell - Member of Board of Directors, Chairman of New York City Committee (#7)
  - Photographs (Paderewski Testimonial Fund Board members) (#8)
- Administration - Incorporation; Tax Matters
  - Incorporation, articles of by-laws (Dover, Delaware) (#9)
  - Tax
    - Information (#10)
    - U.S. Government withholding tax (#11)
    - N.Y. City (#12)
    - N.Y. State reports (#13)
- General ledger (#1) (Box 4)
- Miscellaneous booklets, pamphlets (not Paderewski Testimonial Fund) on Poland, The Polish Review, etc. (#2)
- A - General, 1941-1946 (#1) (Box 5)
- American Overseas Aid (#2)
- Auditors - Deloitte, Plender, Griffitho, and Co. (1954 - succeeded by Haskins and Sells) (#3)
- Appeals - Polish families and groups (#4)
- Alabama Chests, 1943-1944 (#5)
- Arizona Comm.
  - Phoenix (Henry T. Cuthbert, 1941-1947) (#6)
  - Tucson (Mrs. Eleanor Altman, 1941-1944) (#7)
- Arizona Chests, 1942-1943 (#8)
- Arkansas Chests, 1942- (#9)
- B - General, 1941-1947 (for Belgian American Educational Fund, see box 10 and 11) (#10)
- British War Relief Society, 1942-1944 (#11)
- Budget (Paderewski Fund), 1943-1946 (#12)
- C - General, 1941-1947 (#13)
- Canada, 1940-1942 (#14)
- Care, 1945-trough 1949 (#1) (Box 6)
- Audits
  - Co-operative for American Remittances to Everywhere, Inc., 1952-1957 (#2)
  - Co-operative for American Remittance to Europe, Inc., 1949-1951 (#3)
- Mrs. Andrew Carnegie (#4)
- Commission for International Education, 1946-1947 (#5)
- Commission for Polish Relief, Inc. (Secretary Maurice Pate), 1940-1942 (#6)
- Histories - Committees (#7)
- Committees of Paderewski Fund, letters and bulletins (#8)
- Committee lists (#9)
- Community Chests and Councils, 1942 (#10)
- Council - Foreign Voluntary Agencies in Poland, 1946 (#11)
- Community Chests (Chests - general), 1942-1943 (#12)
- California Committees
  - General (#13)
  - Berkeley - Mrs. Samuel Marks, 1941-1945 (#14)
  - Carmel - Mrs. Caroline Picket and Noel Sullivan, 1941-1947 (#15)
  - Fresno - Mrs. Thos. Risley, 1941-1944 (#1) (Box 7)
  - Hollywood
    - Alan Mowbray, 1941-1944-1945 (#2)
    - O'Connor, 1939-1940 (#3)
  - Long Beach - Mrs. Fred Bixby, 1943 (#4)
  - Los Angeles
    - Friends of Poland - John Thomson, 1941-1944 (#5)
    - United Polish Society of Los Angeles, 1941-1944 (#6)
    - Consul Lech T. Nimeo, 1940-1943 (#7)
  - Napa - Miss Gertrude Lamden, 1942-1945 (#8)
  - Oakland - Dr. Geo. Reinle, 1941-1944 (#9)
  - Palo Alto - A. C. Giese, 1941-1945 (#10)
  - Pasadena - Mrs. Robert Millikan, 1941-1943 (#11)
  - Salinas - Chas. Butner, 1943 (#12)
  - San Diego
    - Louis van Norman, 1942-1947 (#13)
    - Irene Yasinka, 1941-1942 (#14)
  - San Fernando - Mrs. Martha Visser (#15)
  - San Francisco
    - Raymond Armsby, 1941-1946 (#16)
    - Committee newsclippings (#17)
    - San Francisco Committee, from 1939 October (#1) (Box 8)
    - Polish Consul W. Sokolowski, 1942-1945 (#2)
  - San Jose - Mrs. John W. Davy, 1943 (#3)
  - Santa Barbara - Richard Crane, 1941-1945 (#4)
  - Santa Cruz - Mrs. B. B. Wilder, 1943 (#5)
  - Van Nuys, 1940-1941 Mrs. H. O. Drelinkiewicz and Rekwart (Chairman) (#6)
- California Chests
  - B - R (#7)
  - S - Z (#8)
  - Polish Groups Cooperating, 1942-1945 (#9)
- Colorado Committee, Denver - A. L. Forsyth, 1941-1943 (#10)
- Colorado Chests, Denver - Fort Collins (#11)
- Connecticut Committees
  - Hartford - Dr. R. B. Ogilby, 1941-1943 (#12)
  - New Britain - Maria Soroka, 1941-1942 (#13)
  - New Canaan - L. E. Hubbelly, 1941-1947 (#14)
  - New Heaven
    - Deane Keller, 1941-1943 (#15)
    - Mrs. C. B. Hogan, 1939-1940 (#16)
  - West Hartford - K. M. Larkum, 1942-1943 (#1) (Box 9)
- Polish Group Cooperating - Connecticut, 1941 (#2)
- Connecticut Chests, 1942 (#3)
- D - General, 1941-1949 (#4)
- Delaware Committee, Wilmington - Mrs. C. Greenwalt, 1941-1943 (#5)
- D.C.
  - Madame Gladys Ciechanowska (Polish Embassy) (#6)
  - Polish Embassy, 1941-1944-1948 (#7)
- D.C. Washington
  - Advisory Committee on Voluntary Foreign Aid
    - 1950-1952 (#8)
    - 1946-1947-1948-1949 (#9)
  - President's War Relief Control Board
    - 1945 (#10)
    - 1944 (#11)
    - 1941-1943 (#12)
    - Directives
      - 1942-1946 (#13)
      - 1941-1942 (#14)
  - State Department, 1939-1940 (#15)
- District of Columbia - Columbia Chests, 1942-1943 (#1) (Box 10)
- Washington, D.C. Committee
  - Mrs. Frank Simonds
    - 1939-1940 (#2)
    - 1941-1945
  - Mrs. Adam Gordon, 1946 (#3)
- E - General, 1941-1949 (#4)
- F - General, 1941-1949 (#4A)
- Food packages to Poland (concerns handling) (#5)
- Florida - General Committee Correspondence (#6)
- Florida Chests, 1942 (#7)
- G - General, 1941-1947 (#8)
- Georgia Chests
  - Atlanta, 1942
  - Savannah, 1942-1943 (#9)
- H - General, 1941-1949 (#10)
- Hoover Institution Library - correspondence re matters sent to Hoover Library (C. E. Rothwell) (#11)
- I - General, 1942-1943-1949) (#12)
- Idaho Committee - Kellogg (S. A. Easton), 1939-1946 (#13)
- Illinois, Chicago
  - American Friends of Poland (Chicago Chapter), 1941-1943 (#14)
  - American Polish National Council (#15)
  - Miss Florence Bartlett, 1941 (#16)
  - Gamma Phi Beta, 1942 (#17)
  - Miss Osterbera's visit, 1941 (#18)
  - Polish Civilian War Relief (Mrs. A. Mix), 1941-1944 (#19)
  - Polish Consul - Dr. Karol Ripa (#20)
  - Polish National Alliance - President Charles Rozmarek, 1945 (#21)
  - Polish Organizations (#22)
  - Polish Roman Catholic Union (#23)
    - Archives and Museum, 1944 (#1) (Box 11)
  - Polish Women's Alliance - Mrs. H. B. Wolowska, 1945-1946 (#2)
  - American Relief for Poland, 1950-1952 (#3)
  - Polish War Relief, 1946-1949 and American Relief for Poland, from 1946 February (#4)
  - Polish War Relief, 1945 (#5)
  - American Relief for Poland - "Report on Organization and Operation of Mission in Poland, December 1945 to January 1947" by Henry J. Osinski (#6)
  - Polish War Relief, 1944 (#7)
  - Polish American Council - Polish War Relief
    - 1942-1943 (#8)
    - 1944 (#9)
- Illinois Committee
  - Chicago
    - Chauncey McCormick, 1939-1946 (#10)
    - Gen. R. E. Wood, 1940-1942 (#11)
  - Peoria - Lillian MacKinnon, 1942 (#12)
  - Urbana - George Goble, 1940-1941 (#13)
- Illinois Chests, 1942-1943 (#14)
- Indiana Committee (Box 12)
  - Indianapolis
    - Mrs. H. M. Woollen, 1946-1948-1953 (Irma Woollen Medical Library) (#1)
    - Medical Library Accounts, 1945-1947 (#2)
    - Mrs. Woollen
      - 1945 (#3)
      - 1944 (#4)
      - 1943 (#5)
      - 1941-1942 (#6)
      - Bookplates (#7)
    - M. D. Carrei, 1939-1946 (#8)
  - South Bend - Miss Mary Ilasz, 1941-1945 (#9)
- Indiana Chests, 1942-1944 (#10)
- Iowa Chests (Cedar Rapids, Centerville, 1942) (#11)
- J - General, 1941-1949 (#12)
- Jones Survey, John. P. (#13)
- K - General, 1941-1949 (#14)
- Mrs. Charlotte Kellogg correspondence and wires to and from headquarters
  - 1941 (#15)
  - 1942 (#1) (Box 13)
  - 1943 (#2)
  - 1944 to 1945 December (#3)
  - 1946 April to 1947 September (#4)
- University of Krakow (#5)
- Kansas Committee - correspondence (#6)
- Kansas Chests, 1942 (Wichita, Topeka, Kansas City) (#7)
- Kentucky - Committee correspondence (#8)
- Kentucky Chests (Louisville, Lexington, 1942) (#9)
- L - General, 1941 to 1949 (#10)
- Labor League for Human Rights (U.N. Relief) - American Federation of Labor (#11)
- Laski - for the blind (#12)
- Lists - bulletin mailing list (#13)
- Louisiana Chests (New Orleans, 1942) (#14)
- Mc - General (#15)
- M - General, 1939-1947 (#1) (Box 14)
- Medical Foundations, 1947 (#2)
- Maine Committees
  - Bar Harbor - H. L. Satterlee, 1941
  - York Village - Elizabeth Perkins, 1944 (#3)
- Maine Chests (Bangor-Brewer, 1943, Portland, 1942) (#4)
- Maryland Committee, Baltimore
  - Miss K. E. Lucke, 1939-1943 (#5)
  - Mrs. White, 1942-1947 (#6)
- Maryland Chests (Baltimore, 1942-1943) (#7)
- Massachusetts Committees
  - Boston
    - B. W. Warren, Jr.
      - 1941-1949 (#8)
      - 1939-1940 (#9)
    - Friends of Polish Culture - Dr. Tadeusz Raczynski, 1945 (#10)
  - Greenfield - Paul Gorecki (Polish Relief Committee), 1941-1943 (#11)
  - Stockbridge - Mrs. A. Rodzinski, 1941 (#12)
  - Worcester
    - Mrs. E. Krawczynski, 1941-1946 (#13)
    - Polish Jr. League, 1941 (#14)
- Polish groups cooperating (Massachusetts) (#15)
- Massachusetts Chests (#16)
- Michigan Committees
  - Ann Arbor, etc., 1941 (#17)
  - Detroit, 1939-1943 (#18)
- Polish groups cooperating (Michigan) (#19)
- Michigan Chests (#20)
- Minnesota Committees (Box 15)
  - Duluth - Rev. F. T. Schultz, 1943 (#1)
  - Minneapolis - Mrs. S. Hawks, 1940-1947 (#2)
- Minnesota Polish Groups (#3)
- Minnesota Chests, 1942-1943 (#4)
- Mississippi Chests (Jackson, 1942-1943) (#5)
- Missouri Committees
  - Kansas City - Mrs. Henry Haskell, 1939-1946 (#6)
  - St. Louis
    - J. L. Davis, 1942-1947 (#7)
    - David Gray, 1941-1943 (#8)
- Missouri Chests, 1942-1943 (#9)
- Montana - General Committee (#10)
- Montana Chests (Billings, 1943) (#11)
- N - General, 1941-1946 (#12)
- National Federation of Music Clubs - Mrs. Vincent Ober, 1941 (#13)
- Rev. W. Coleman Nevils, 1941-1952 (#14)
- Nebraska (#15)
- Nebraska Chests (Omaha, 1942) (#16)
- Nevada Committee (Reno - Samuel Platt, 1943-1946) (#17)
- Nevada Chests (Reno, 1942-1943) (#18)
- New Hampshire Committees
  - Concord - Mrs. J. L. Smith, 1941-1944 (#19)
  - Dartmouth - Eric Kelly, 1939-1946 (#20)
- New Hampshire Chests, 1942 (#21)
- New Jersey Committees (Box 16)
  - Montclair - Mrs. Anderson, 1941 (#1)
  - Newark
    - Mrs. Conklin, 1941 (#2)
    - Mrs. F. Fuld, 1941 (#3)
    - Mrs. Slowinska, 1942-1943 (#4)
  - Princeton - R. Lindabury, 1939-1944 (#5)
  - Trenton - John Colt, 1941-1943 and Anthony Brenzk, 1942-1943 (#6)
- New Jersey - Polish groups cooperating (#7)
- New Jersey Chests (#8)
- New York Buffalo - Rev. Justin Figas (#9)
- New York State Committees
  - Albany - Stanislaw Kosinski, 1941-1943 (#10)
  - Binghamton (#11)
  - Buffalo (#12)
  - Newburgh - Mrs. Wallach, 1942 (#13)
  - Poughkeepsie - Prof. Gordon ?, 1941? (#14)
  - Rochester
    - Dr. H. Hanson
    - Miss Josephine Dunham, 1941-1946 (#15)
  - Syracuse - Dr. Wm. Scheding, 1941 (#16)
  - Utica - Arthur Foley, 1940-1941 (#17)
  - Yonkers - H. Meyer, 1941-1945 (#18)
- New York State - Polish groups cooperating (#19)
- New York Chests (#20)
- American Council of Voluntary Agencies
  - 1950-1951 (#21)
  - 1948-1949 (#22)
- American Council of Voluntary Agencies for Foreign Service (Box 17)
  - 1944-1945 (#1)
  - 1946-1949 (#2)
- Federal Reserve Bank (N.Y. City, 1941-1945 - Foreign Prop. Control Dept.) (#3)
- Kosciuszko Foundation, 1940, 1943, 1948 (#4)
- NYC - Medical and Surgical Relief Committee, 1945 (#5)
- Motion Picture Industry (U.N. Week), 1942-1944 (#6)
- National Catholic Welfare Conference (Washington D.C., NYC), 1942-1949 (#6A)
- National City Bank (orders for payments)
  - 1954-1959 (#7)
  - 1950-1953 (#8)
  - 1941-1949 (#9)
- National Information Bureau, 1941, 1946, 1948 (#10)
- National War Fund
  - 1943, 1947, 1948 (#11)
  - Budget, publicity, etc. (#12)
- New York War Fund, 1944-1945 (#13)
- New York City - Polish Consul Sylwin Strakacz, 1941-1946 (#14)
- Polish Embassy (NYC) - Financial Counselor, 1941 (#15)
- NY - Polish Government Information Center, 1943-1944 (#16)
- Polish Institute of Arts and Science (#17)
- Polish Social Service Bureau, 1940-1943 (#1) (Box 18)
- New York - Rockefeller Fn., 1942-1947 (#2)
- Carleton Smith (New York City), 1941 (#3)
- New York City - Sigismond Slojowski (#4)
- New York City Headquarters
  - Eagle Pins (#5)
  - Lease (#6)
  - 37th E. 36th St. (and 39th E. 35th St.) (#7)
  - Insurance (N.Y.), 1942-1947 (#8)
  - Northwestern Storage Warehouse (#9)
  - Insurance policies (#10)
  - Personnel (#11)
  - Program Arrangements Section (#12)
  - Publicity (Chas. Gamble and Associates) (#13)
  - Utilities (#14)
  - J. A. Want, organization (#15)
- Bills, cancelled checks (1945 April-1946 October) (Box 19)
- Miscellaneous correspondence (Mrs. Edward Schelling), 1940 November-1941 September (#1) (Box 20)
  - National Paderewski Testimonial
    - Note from Eleanor Roosevelt, 1940 December 2
    - 1941 February 15-22, correspondence - Chairman and Mrs. Ernest Schelling (#1A)
- Correspondence with Hartwell Jobson and Kibbee (#2)
- National Paderewski Testimonial
  - No.3, 1941 February 15-22; Mrs. Ernest Schelling (list of concert programs) (#3)
  - No.4, 1941 February 15-22; Mrs. Ernest Schelling (contributions, statement of accounts, payments to Hartwell, Jobson, and Kibbee (#4)
  - No.5 - report, circular letters, publicity releases (#5)
  - No.6 - sponsoring committee (#6)
- Paderewski Testimonial - Golden Book, 1941 (No.7) (#7)
- National Paderewski Testimonial - Homage to Paderewski (published by Boosey and Hawkes, Inc., NYC) (#8)
- Homage to Paderewski - concert at home of Samuel L. Barlow, 1942 February 27 (#9)
- Testimonial Concert
  - 1941 January (at Mrs. Carnegie's home) (#10)
  - 1941 March 8 (Palm Beach, Florida-Carleton Smith) (#11)
- New York City - Testimonial Concert, Carnegie Hall - Nadia Boulanger, 1941 April 4 (New York Philharmonic Symphony) (#1) (Box 21)
- Paderewski Testimonial Day, 1941 April 18 (exhibition at Levy Gallery chaired by Mrs. Otto Preminger) (#2)
- Garden lectures, 1942 March-April (Hugh Findlay) and correspondence with Hugh Findlay until 1945 (#3)
- New York City
  - Polish Dolls (Women's International Exposition, 1942 December) (#4)
  - Town Hall, 1943 February 8 (Stanley Nowak of Harvard) (#5)
- New York City Committee
  - 1939-1940 (Col. W. J. Donovan) (#6)
  - 1941-1942 (Mrs. Chauncey Waddell) (#7)
  - 1942-1944 (Mrs. Ernest Schelling) (#8)
  - Brooklyn - Frank Serri, 1939-1940 (#9)
  - Brooklyn, Queens, Bronx - Polish Groups (#10)
- North Caroline Committee - Raleigh (Mrs. R. L. McMillan, 1941) (#11)
- North Dakota Chests
  - 1942 (#12)
  - (Fargo, 1940) (#13)
- O - General, 1940-1949 (#14)
- Ohio Committee
  - Akron
    - Konarski, 1941-1942
    - Piotrowski, 1946 (#15)
  - Cincinnati (C. H. Thuman, 1941-1943) (#16)
  - Cleveland (Box 22)
    - Mrs. A. Rodzinski, 1939-1943 (#1)
    - Thos. Jones, 1939-1940 (#2)
- Ohio, Cleveland - Poland War Sufferers Aid Committee (Hon. Jos. F. Sawicki) (#3)
- Ohio Committee
  - Columbus (Paul Clapp, 1939-1940) (#4)
  - Toledo (Grove Patterson, 1940-1942) (#5)
- Ohio - Polish Groups (Ohio Chests, 1942-1943) (#6)
- Ohio Chests, 1942-1943 (#6A)
- Oklahoma Committee - Tulsa, 1939-1940 (#7)
- Oklahoma Chests (#8)
- Oregon Committee - Portland (Mrs. Spencer, 1941-1945) (#9)
- Oregon - Polish Groups (United Polish Societies) (#10)
- Oregon Chests
  - Portland, 1942
  - Salem, 1942 (#11)
- P - General (1941-1947-1951) (#12)
- Paderewski Fund for Polish Relief
  - 1941-1943 (Mr. and Mrs. Guido Pantaleoni) (#13)
  - 1940 (photos of committee members, etc. - Mrs. Eleanor Roosevelt, Mrs. Kellogg, Mrs. Schelling, Hon. Ct. Potocki, Mayor La Guardia, Arthur Rubenstein, Col. Donovan, etc.) (#14)
- Paderewski Foundation Inc., New York, 1951-1953 (President - Edward S. Witkowski) (#15)
- Post-war work in Poland (#16)
- Public health in Poland (report, 1949, put out by Polish Research and Information Service) (#17)
- Mrs. T. L. Purdy (#18)
- Pennsylvania Department of Welfare (Harrisburg, 1941-1942) (#19)
- Pennsylvania Committee
  - Erie (T. P. Dunn, 1941-1942) (#20)
  - Philadelphia
    - (Anne Brock, 1940-1942) (#21)
    - Mrs. Edward Bok, 1939-1940 (#1) (Box 23)
    - Polish Relief Committee, 1941-1945 (Leon. L. Kolankiewicz) (#2)
  - Pittsburgh
    - Horace Baker, 1940-1946 (#3)
    - Polish Falcons of America, 1941-1946 (Dr. T. A. Starzynski) (#4)
    - Counsul H. Sztark, 1940-1946 (#5)
  - Scranton (Sidney Grabowski, 1940-1942) (#6)
- Pennsylvania Polish Groups (#7)
- Pennsylvania Chests, 1942-1943 (#8)
- Souvenir Program of The Paderewski Fund-10th Anniversary Ball, 1958 November 15; correspondence with Ignacy Jan Paderewski and Madame Wilkonska, 1939-1941 (#9)
- Paderewski birthday card (80th birthday-1940 November 6) (#10)
- Luncheon - Lotos Club, 1941 January 7 (Madame Wilkonska and Ignacy Jan Paderewski) (#11)
- Paderewski Memorial Exhibition, 1941 July-August (#12)
- Paderewski Memorials (Hoffman Exhibition, 1942 June 24), the CBS program, 1942 July 8 (#13)
- Paderewski Fund Projects (Box 24)
  - Special Assistance Committee
    - Britain
      - Reports
        - 1943 (#1)
        - 1944 (#2)
        - 1945 (#3)
      - Remittances, 1941-1945 (#4)
      - Reports
        - 1941 (#5)
        - 1942 (#6)
    - France (Madame Sosnicka) (#7)
      - Paris (Madame Sosnicka, 1945-1949) (#1) (Box 25)
      - Vichy (Madame Sosnicka, 1941-1942) (#2)
    - Sweden - Stockholm, 1941-1946 (#3)
    - Switzerland
      - Lausanne (Madame Lübke, 1941-1947) (#4)
      - Student Relief, 1940-1942 (#5)
  - Food relief parcels to Poland, 1946 (#6, #7)
- Special work (Box 26)
  - England (Countess C. Raczynska - British Isles) (#1)
  - Correspondence with Prince Olgierd Czartoryski (Rio de Janeiro, Brazil) (#2)
- Monthly reports (loose in box) re: Rules of Neutrality Act of 1939 (#3)
- Pamphlet: The Farm Surplus and Hungry People, A proposal by CARE, 1954 February (#4)
- Ledger - record of committee expenses (#5)
- R - General, 1940-1949 (#1) (Box 27)
- Relatives - seeking (#2)
- Dr. Charles Rosenberg (#3)
- Rhode Island Committee - Providence (Mrs. Sharpe, 1942) (#4)
- Rhode Island Chests (Providence, Woonsocket, 1942) (#5)
- S - General (#6)
- South Carolina Chests (Columbia, Greenville, 1942) (#7)
- South Dakota Chests (Aberdeen, Sioux Falls, 1942) (#8)
- T - General, 1940-1949 (#9)
- Texas Committee
  - Dallas (Stanley Marcus, 1941-1946, and Marion Flagg) (#10)
  - Houston (St. John Garwood, 1939-1943, and Miss Grace Godard) (#11)
- Texas Chests (#12)
- U - General, 1941-1943 (#13)
- Unitarian Service Committee, 1945-1949 (#14)
- U.N.R.R.A.
  - Transportation for Doctors (#15)
  - Clothing collection, 1945-1946 (#16)
- Utah Chests - Salt Lake City, 1942 (#17)
- V - General, 1941-1942 (#18)
- Vermont Committee - Burlington (Jos. Winterbotham, 1939-1941) (#19)
- Virginia Committee - Alexandria (Mrs. Philip D. Mosser, 1939-1941) (#20)
- Virginia Chests, 1942 (#21)
- Volunteers, 1939 (#22)
- W - General, 1940-1949 (#1) (Box 28)
- Mrs. Pat Washington, 1941-1946 (British Committee for Polish Welfare, London (#2)
- Washington Committee - Seattle (Stephen Kluck, 1942-1948, and Mrs. Chas Richards) (#3)
- Washington Chests, 1942-1943 (#3A)
- West Virginia Chests, 1942 (#4)
- Wisconsin Committee
  - Milwaukee (C. E. Saskowski, 1941-1942) (#4A)
  - Stevens Point (Ernest Lilien) (#5)
- Wisconsin Chests (Green Bay, Kenosha, Madison, Milwaukee, Racine, 1942) (#6)
- Wyoming Chests (Caster, 1942) (#7)
- X, Y, Z - General, 1941-1946 (#8)
- YMCA - Polish branch (Mr. Paul Super) (#9)
- Bulletins - Paderewski Fund for Polish Relief Nos. 1-3 and Paderewski Testimonial Fund - bulletins and releases from 1941-1948 (#10)
- Paderewski Testimonial Fund (PTF) - bulletin No.1, 1941 May (2 copies) (#11)
- Paderewski Fund for Polish Relief (PFPR) - bulletins No.1, 2, 3 (1941 January-April) (#12)
- Paderewski Testimonial Fund bulletins
  - No. 2, 1941 June (#13)
  - No. 3, 1941 July (2 copies) (#14)
  - No. 4, 1941 September (2 copies) (#15)
  - No. 5, 1942 January (2 copies) (#16)
  - No. 6, 1942 March (2 copies) (#17)
  - No. 7, 1942 July (#18)
  - No. 8, 1943 October (#19)
  - 1944 January (no number) (#20)
  - No. 9, 1944 July (#21)
  - No. 10, 1944 September (#22)
  - No. 11, 1945 February (#23)
  - No. 12, 1948 July (#24)
- Paderewski Testimonial Fund, Inc. - Press releases, 1940 December-1948 October (#1) (Box 29)
- Miscellaneous circulars (#2)
- The official seal stamp (#3)
- Microfilm - inventory of Paderewski Hospital (2 rolls) (#4)
- Polish School of Medicine - at the University of Edinburgh, London, 1942 (1 copy in English, another in Polish) (#5)
- Early Files (Box 30)
  - A - General, 1939-1940 (#1)
  - Allied Relief, 1939-1940 (#2)
  - American Legion, 1940 (#3)
  - American Red Cross, 1939-1940 (#4)
  - Answers to current questions (#5)
  - Appeals (#6)
  - Articles of Incorp. and by-laws (#7)
  - B - General (#7A)
  - Bishop's Commission for Polish Relief (#8)
  - Broadcast - NBC, 1940 April 16 (#9)
  - Julien Bryan (#10)
  - Bulletins
    - Commission for Polish Relief
    - The Paderewski Fund for Polish Relief
    - Paderewski Testimonial Fund, Inc. and Paderewski Hospital (#11)
  - C - General, 1939-1940 (#12)
  - California Committee - General (#13)
  - California
    - Hollywood Committee
      - Thaddeus Wronski, 1940 (#14)